Simão Lopes

Data Analyst

Former 15-yearlong content creator and IT trainer, with a background in coding in C++ and Oracle database admin, transitioning into a Data Scientist role after completing Iron Hack Bootcamp. Hands-on experience in machine learning in Python, pandas, Scikit-Learn, MySQL and Exploratory data analysis, pursuing continuous personal and professional growth, driven by knowledge and efficiency.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teacher assistant – Data Analytics

2022

IronHack

- Evaluate students progress during the 9 weeks Full-time Data Analytics bootcamp.
- Coaches, mentor and guide students on programming, analytical and machine learning projects.

IT trainer 2018 - 2022

Open Space Formação e Soluções Empresariais

- Trained 20+ companies in advanced Excel, dashboards building and working with SQL-imported data.
- Trained 10 social integration courses to long-time unemployed people, 300+ people in total.
- Advised 4 big companies in business planning with Microsoft Visio.

Content creator 2019 - 2020

Eattasty

 Delivered 50+ monthly food photography images for an online shopping website, decreasing the time of each photoshoot to 1H.

Content creator 2005 - 2020

Concept photo

- Created more than 40 video productions per year for 15 years.
- Created institutional videos and photos for 50+ different retail and industrial companies.
- Conducted 4 big public events that gathered more than 500 people.
- Performed colour grading for 1 national TV show with 10 episodes.
- Managed a 4-member streaming team for 3 years broadcasting more than 15 events a year.

EDUCATION

Data Science 2022

IronHack Boot Camp, Online

- Built Tableau dashboard using data from MySQL databases and python cleaned CSV generated files.
- Machine learning models in Python, with great self-study in hyper tuning.
- Data cleaning, MySQL/Python.
- Programming in Python, advanced pandas, Web Scraping and API.

Information Systems Engineering

2008

Instituto Politecnico de Viana do Castelo Degree in Information Systems

CONTACT

- Viana do Castelo, PT (Open to Remote)
- · +351 916241077
- · simaocarmolopes@gmail.com
- · linkedin.com/in/simao-lopes
- · github.com/Simao-Lopes

SKILLS

- · API and Web scraping.
- · SQL.
- · Regex.
- · Data Visualization.
- · Exploratory Data Analysis.
- . Git
- · Machine Learning.
- Python
- · Tableau.
- · Scikit-learn.
- · Pandas.

Data Analytics Projects

Art type identifier

https://github.com/Simao-Lopes/art.i

Identifies the art movement from a provided painting.

- API, Scraping, BeautifullSoup, Kmeans cluster, Keras, Resnet.
- · Song advisor.

https://github.com/Simao-Lopes/labweb-scraping-single-page

Suggests a song from an input string.

- API, Scraping, BeautifullSoup, Kmeans cluster.
- · Fires in Portugal.

https://github.com/Simao-Lopes/Fire-Project

Modelling the amount of burnt area in Portugal's forest fires.

- Pandas, Seaborn, SK-Learn, RandomForestRegressor, SQL.

OTHER

- Advanced user of Adobe Creative Suite.
- · Book lover.
- · Electronics enthusiast.

